Finding aid for the Albert Kahn Associates records, 1825-2014
Bentley Historical Library
- Architectural Drawings
  - Drawing Record Cards, 1920-1958
    - Job No. 1860-A -- 1867-X (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1868 -- 1892-T (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1893-C -- 1905-M (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1905-N -- 1917-S (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1918 -- 1939 (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1941-A -- 1950-BY (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1950-C -- 1966-G (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1967 -- 1985-B (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1985-E -- 1988-R (Box 151)
    - Job No. 1989 -- 2024-Z (Box 151)
    - Job No. 2026 -- 2057-B (Box 151)
    - Job No. 2058 -- 2067-Y (Box 151)
    - Job No. 2068 -- 2076-B (Box 151)
    - Job No. 2076-D -- 2088-L (Box 151)
    - Job No. 2090 -- 2095-AQ (Box 151)
    - Job No. 2095-C -- 2110-H (Box 151)
    - Job No. 2110-J -- 2113-Q (Box 151)
Related Materials
The Albert Kahn Family Papers were donated in 2002 by Carol Kahn, daughter of Albert Kahn's son Edgar. Included in this collection are the personal correspondence of Albert and his wife Ernestine, family photographs and a folder of materials related to the community's efforts to "Save Old Main" (1989), University of Michigan Hospital, which her grandfather designed in 1919.
The William L. Clements Papers and the Marion L. Burton Papers include correspondence and committee minutes associated with Albert Kahn's tenure as Consulting Architect for the University of Michigan in the early 1920s. The letters document his service on the important "Committee of Five," which oversaw the university's Comprehensive Building Program during a time of prolific construction on the Ann Arbor campus.
The University of Michigan Architectural Drawings Collection contains a number of renderings and drawings of Kahn's buildings, including the Natural Science Building and the Thomas H. Simpson Memorial Institute for Medical Research.
The University of Michigan Museum of Art Records document two exhibitions related to Kahn's work: "Albert Kahn: An American Architect Abroad" (1996) and "Albert Kahn: Inspiration for the Modern" (2001). The materials associated with the 1996 exhibit include the list of Kahn's travel sketches from trips to Europe in 1891, 1912 and 1924-35, which were hung in the show and are in the permanent collection of the Museum of Art.
University of Michigan Museum of Art. Images of 273 of Albert Kahn's sketches of European architecture, drawn during his trips of 1891, 1911-1912, 1920, and 1924-1925, are available for online viewing at the website of the University of Michigan Museum of Art. The Museum of Art holds these drawings in its permanent collection.